At 9:27 am
话说在那主体104年3月24号
on the 24th of March 2015,
的早晨, 9点27分
a plane got in contact with the Marseilles enroute control center.
一架航班联络了马赛航路管制中心
It was an Airbus A320-211
那是架空客A320-211,
operated by Germanwings
由德国之翼航空运营
headed from Barcelona to Dusseldorf.
正从巴塞罗那飞往杜塞尔多夫
Everything seemed normal.
一切似乎如常
The captain read back the air traffic controller's clearance at 9:30, allowing him to fly to an enroute waypoint.
9点30分, 机长复诵了空管允许他飞往某个航路点的放行指令,
Only a few minutes later, something was off.
然而几分钟后, 事情不对劲了起来
The control center in Marseilles
马赛的管制中心
saw that the altitude for the aircraft
发现飞机的高度
was around thirty thousand feet,
在三万英尺左右徘徊
almost two thousand feet lower than the original cruise altitude.
比原定的巡航高度低了差不多两千英尺
and declining.
且其高度仍在持续下降
Marseilles contacted the plane
马赛空管联系了航班
and asked what altitude the plane was cleared for,
并询问飞机获准飞行的高度
but they received no response at all
但他们没有收到回复
over the next 30 seconds,
之后的三十秒内
Marseilles tried to contact the flight crew two more times.
空管又试了两次
No answer.
还是没有答复
At 9:34 the control center tried a different frequency,
34分, 空管再次尝试用不同频率联系
but again no response.
机组仍然没有答复
From 9:35 until 9:39
从35分到39分
the Marseilles control center tried to contact the flight crew multiple times over different frequencies.
马赛空管坚持多次用不同频率联系机组
An air traffic controller from the French air defense system
另一架飞机 以及一位法国防空系统的管制员
also tried as well as another aircraft
也尝试联系德翼9525
but each time
然而
no response from Germanwings flight 9525
德翼9525却一直没有回复
At 9:40 radar contact was lost
9点40分, 德翼9525的雷达信号消失了
the French air traffic controllers triggered a distress phase
法国空管启动了紧急程序
declaring that the aircraft and its occupants
宣布该飞行器及其乘员
were in imminent danger and required immediate assistance
处于迫在眉睫的危机之中并需要他人立即援助
At 9:41 am flight Germanwings 9525
41分,
crashed into the side of a mountain in the Alps.
德翼9525坠毁在了阿尔卑斯山脉的一侧
What happened?
到底发生了什么？
The crash occurred on a remote mountain.
事故发生在偏远山区
Because there was no access by road,
山上没通公路
emergency crew had to be brought in via helicopter.
救援人员不得不乘直升机前往
The plane was completely destroyed:
飞机撞的粉碎
the debris field vast but the pieces of the craft small.
碎片散步的区域很大, 而碎片本身却很小
The cockpit voice and flight recorder were found in the same week
驾驶舱语音记录器和飞行数据记录仪在同一周被发现
although they were both severely damaged.
不过它们也被摔的惨烈
When flight investigators stitched together the data
当调查员整合完毕数据
a story of intentional action formed.
The plane was hijacked,
飞机被劫持了
but not by terrorists.
只不过不是被恐怖分子劫持的
Let's go back.
我们来回顾一下
After the aircraft leveled off at its cruise altitude,
9点半, 飞机离开巡航高度后
the captain left the cockpit to go to the bathroom at 9:30
机长离开驾驶舱去了厕所
While he was in the bathroom,
他在厕所里时
the plane was almost immediately set
飞机立刻被设置了
for a different altitude in the cockpit
一个不同的高度
At 9:34, the captain came back and requested
34分, 机长上完厕所回来
The door was locked.
但他被锁在了驾驶舱门外
As he stood in front of that cockpit door
站在舱门前
the captain began to understand.
机长明白了
The co-pilot had hijacked the plane
副机长劫持了这架飞机
and he had no way of getting in.
而他没法进入驾驶舱
After 2001,
911事件后
cockpits were changed in order to protect those flying the plane from potential hijackers
飞机驾驶舱被改装以防止可能的劫机发生
To enter the cockpit,
机组成员想进入驾驶舱
a crew member has to call the cockpit on the intercom
就必须按键盘上的井号
and press the pound key on a keypad,
用对讲系统呼叫驾驶舱
which buzzes the cockpit.
让驾驶舱里的人听到嗡嗡声
At that moment the pilot can switch the door control
这之后飞行员可以控制舱门
from norm to unlock,
将其切换到解锁状态
and the crew member can enter.
随后机组成员便可进门
The crew is also given emergency codes
机组也有应急密码
which they can use if there are concerns for those in the cockpit.
可在驾驶舱内人员出问题时使用
in that case the crew member will use the emergency code on the keypad
机组可以在键盘上输入应急密码
triggering a 30 second timer
30秒后,
and the cockpit door will open for 5 seconds
舱门就会打开5秒钟
however there are situations where those in the cockpit
然而, 在某种情况下
want to override the access by the crew
譬如被劫机时
like during a hijacking
驾驶舱里的人可以阻止机组成员开门
in that situation the pilots can switch the door control to lock
飞行员可以把舱门切换到锁定状态
overriding all emergency access.
阻止他人用应急密码开门
and it's that mechanism
德翼9525的副机长
that the co-pilot used
正是使用了这个机制
to permanently lock access to the cockpit
在飞机开始下降时
while the plane began to descend.
锁定了驾驶舱门
The captain was locked out of the cockpit
机长被锁在了外边
without any control.
无法操控飞机
At 9:39 the cockpit voice recorder
39分时,
picked up violent blows on the cockpit door.
语音记录器录下了舱门上传来的猛烈撞击声
The captain had repeatedly tried breaking in to gain access
机长尝试破门
but the cockpit door was reinforced.
但舱门为反武装劫机而设计
Made to withstand armed hijackers
十分坚固
the captain stood little chance.
机长胜算微渺
In the last minutes
在最后的几分钟里
the passengers crew and Captain
机组与乘客
all knew that the plane was going down.
都了发现飞机正在坠毁
No one survived the crash.
机上144位乘客
144 passengers
4位乘务员
four cabin crew
机长及副机长
and the captain and co-pilot died.
无人幸存
Amongst the passengers was an entire school class
乘客中, 有一整个班的孩子
returning from a field trip to Spain.
在西班牙郊游完毕正返校
The captain Patrick Sondenheimer
机长帕特里克·桑德海默
was a 34 year old father of two.
时年34, 膝下二儿
In the aftermath his wife set up a foundation in his name
事后, 机长的妻子以他的名义设立了一家基金会
intended to help children and young people handle grief and crisis.
来帮助儿童及年轻人应对危机与悲伤
He had thousands of total flight hours
机长有数千小时的飞行经验
and his last moments were dedicated to trying to save the plane and passengers.
直到最后一刻, 他还在力图挽救乘客与飞机
以下内容可能引起部分观众不适, 建议观众自行斟酌是否观看
The co-pilot was 27 years old
副机长时年27
and from a young age he was passionate about flying.
从小他就热衷于飞行
His bedroom had posters of Airbus Boeing and Lufthansa
他的卧室里贴着波音、空客与汉莎航空的海报
and he'd become an expert glider pilot as a child.
他小时候就精通于滑翔机驾驶
He joined Lufthansa's Flight Academy straight out of school,
他一毕业就加入了汉莎航空的飞行学院
but only a few months into the program
但仅仅几个月后
he stopped.
他就被停飞了
He was suffering from a deep depressive episode
他正经历着一次严重的抑郁症发作
treated with antidepressants
同时在服用抗抑郁药物
and spent multiple months in the care of a psychiatrist.
并接受了长达数月的治疗
Eventually he received a medical recommendation
最终他收到了一份医疗建议
declaring that he was in remission.
宣布他已处于缓解期
After a few months
数月后
his student pilot license and fit to fly medical certificate were restored,
他的学生飞行员执照与适航医疗证明被恢复
but if he needed any more psychiatric treatment
不过如果仍需要进一步的心理治疗
he'd be grounded from flying.
他就会被停飞
But he continued with his training
但他继续进行训练
until he ran into a problem.
直到撞上南墙
While filling out a document required by the U.S Federal Aviation Administration
在填写一份由美国联邦航空管理局(FAA)要求的文件,
to fly at an Arizona based Lufthansa operated flight school
以在亚利桑那州的一家汉莎航空旗下航校飞行时
he said that he had never been diagnosed
他说他从未被诊断
with any mental disorders.
患有任何精神疾病
This was a lie
这是个谎言
and he got caught.
而他被揭穿了
Lying on an FAA application can lead to a jail offense
在FAA申请中造假可能构成刑事犯罪
or the end of a flying career,
也可能终结他的飞行生涯
but the FAA gave him a second chance.
但FAA给了他第二次机会
He admitted to depression
他承认他患有抑郁症
and was accepted to go to Arizona.
并获得许可前往亚利桑那航校
In 2013 he joined Germanwings
2013年, 他加入了德国之翼航空,
a low-budget Airline owned by Lufthansa.
一家汉莎航空旗下的廉价航空公司
And a year later his depression returned.
一年后, 他的抑郁症又复发了
He thought he was going blind,
他认为他要失明了
visiting ophthalmologists and neurologists multiple times per week
每周都要去看几次眼科医生
because he was seeing stars, halos, flashes of light, streaks, and flying insects
因为他眼前总能看到星星, 光晕, 闪光, 线条与飞虫
But the doctor's scans didn't find much.
但医生进行的扫描却什么都没发现
He was diagnosed with hypochondriacal disorder
他被诊断患有疑病症
*疑病症, 又称健康焦虑障碍
是在没有明确医学根据的情况下, 认定自己患有某种特定疾病的精神病理状态
as well as emergent psychosis from his family doctor.
其家庭医生亦诊断他患有急性精神病
And that doctor urged him to go to a psychiatric clinic,
家庭医生敦促他去精神病院
but he do no such thing.
他当时没去
Instead in January of 2015
但在2015年1月
he returned to the psychiatrist
他去看了精神科医生
that had helped him in the first place.
这一定程度上帮助了他
He received Psychotherapy
他接受了心理治疗
and went on heavy antidepressants
在工作与飞行的同时
while continuing to work and fly.
大量服用抗抑郁药
From February to March
从二月到三月
he received multiple sick notes from multiple doctors.
他收到了来自数位医生处的多份病假条
He wasn't alright and he wanted something to change.
他不好受, 并希望求得改变
Four days before the crash
事故发生的四天前
he turned to his computer to understand the locking mechanism
他打开电脑
on the Airbus A320 cockpit door.
学习A320的驾驶舱门锁定机制
On his outbound flight from Dusseldorf to Barcelona
在从杜塞尔多夫到巴塞罗那的国际航班上
he tested the descent settings for a moment
机长桑德海默在驾驶舱外时
while Sondenheimer was outside the cockpit.
他测试了一下飞机的下降设置
On the return flight
在回程的航班上
he used it to bring down the plane.
他以此让飞机坠毁
How could this have happened?
这本不该发生
Pilots are required to do Health screenings and annual checkups,
飞行员必须进行体检
but mental health is easier overlooked than physical.
不过精神健康比身体健康更容易被忽视
Since pilots operate under an honor system
由于飞行员遵循荣誉制度
they're expected to self-evaluate their health.
他们被期望自行评估其自身健康水平
And this can be an issue.
而这可能是个问题
The co-pilot was declared unfit to work by his doctor,
这位副机长被其医生宣布不适宜继续工作
but he decided to just not tell his employer.
但他本人决定不将此事告知其雇主
But if someone like him is a risk to Public Safety
但假若某人像这位副机长一样可能危害公共安全
a doctor can break doctor-patient confidentiality
医生可以打破医患间保密关系
and report him to authorities.
并向当局举报其患者
So why didn't at least one of the multiple doctors
所以, 为什么这么多写了病假条
who wrote multiple sick notes
并宣布他不适航的医生
and declared him unfit to fly
其中却没有一位
think that the co-pilot may have presented a risk for public safety?
认为这位副机长可能危害公共安全呢？
Enough of a risk
还是说可能的危害足够大
that he couldn't be trusted to report himself?
大到某一位医生没法单独出面举报吗？
We don't know.
我们不得而知
The doctors may have believed the co-pilot was a risk to himself,
医生们也或许认为副机长仅对其自身
but not to others.
而非其他人构成威胁
Being depressed does not make you a killer.
患抑郁症不会让你变成杀人凶手
Or maybe the doctors were just scared.
或许医生们只是害怕
Breaking doctor-patient confidentiality does not come without risks.
打破医患保密并非没有风险
It's even possible cultural factors could have played a role.
文化也可能是医生们闭口不谈的因素之一
Privacy and data protection are valued really highly in Germany.
隐私与数据保护在德国极受重视
But trying to understand why doctor-patient confidentiality wasn't broken
不过, 理解医患保密之间的保密关系到底没被打破的原因
is a dilemma an issue best left to healthcare professionals and ethics professors.
是个最好由医疗专业人员和伦理学教授来处理的两难问题
And unfortunately we're YouTubers.
很遗憾, 我们只是UP主
So we encourage you to read more about it in these articles.
所以我们推荐你通过阅读这些文章来了解更多
Nonetheless when you're watching this today
在你观看这期视频时
it's important to understand that this type of incident
你应当明白
is incredibly unlikely.
发生此类事件的可能性极低
In the aftermath the European Aviation Safety Agency
事故发生后, 欧洲航空安全局
proposed multiple safety regulations.
出台了多项安全规定
Psychological screening for pilots increased
对飞行员的精神健康检测次数增多
and multiple Airlines adopted a two-person in the cockpit at all-time rule
多家航司亦实施了驾驶舱内必须始终有两人的规定
although Lufthansa has recently phased this out.
尽管汉莎航空已于近期取消了这一规定
In 2015 Germanwings was rebranded to Eurowings.
2015年, 德国之翼航空公司更名为欧洲之翼
The decision was made prior to the crash.
这一决策是在坠机事故前做出的
In the end Lufthansa compensated the families of the victims
最后, 汉莎航空对受害者家属进行了赔偿
but there are questions about whether it was enough.
但也存在对赔偿是否足够的质疑
The families have faced losses that no money can heal.
受害者家属所遭受的损失不是金钱可以弥补的
Hopefully you enjoyed this video, it was insanely hard to make.
希望你喜欢这期视频, 它的制作真的非常困难
We love animation and deep research
我们乐于进行深度调查并制作动画
but it's expensive.
但这样做的代价十分高昂
That's why we have sponsors on this channel.
所以接下来是恰饭时间:)
By the way a lot of our animation in particular
我们有一堆动画
actually has a lot to do with math,
制作它们就像做一堆数学高考卷
be it geometry or linear algebra for specific shaders
be like:VS Code&Blender：你好
or code for scripted and procedural animation.
几何&线性代数：那你再看看你后面呢
Both can be exciting and fascinating
原来, 数学也可以这么迷人吗
especially if taught in a playful manner.
哈哈, 那就厉害了(指Brilliant)
That's where Brilliant comes in.
Brilliant不仅在数学上寓教于乐
It gives you skills that can be applied to everything literally,
它还提供在你B上付费的AI课
be it basic logic artificial intelligence data science or physics.
教会你可用于生活方方面面的小知识小巧思,
But it gives it to you in a way that isn't earth-shatteringly boring.
譬如在不触发烟雾报警器的情况下炒好糖色
To try everything brilliant has to offer free for a full 30 days
我们还支持30天免费试用
visit brilliant.org/fern or click on the link in the description.
动动你发财的小手点点屏幕下方小黄车了解更多哦亲
The first 200 of you will get 20 off of Brilliant's annual premium subscription.
刚刚接到通知, 前200位点进链接的宝宝还能喜提8折年度大会员
You always have your phone on you, which means Brilliant always gives you access to learn math and science anywhere
bro的手机不离身,  Brilliant可能倒闭但永不变质的大会员服务也如影随形
even if it's only for a few minutes each day.
时间就是海绵里的水
You can improve your skills while in a tram, walking
给Brilliant挤几滴
or while your significant other is trying to connect with you.
bro的大脑就能LEVEL UP
We personally love the app.
我们私下很喜欢这款APP
There's something incredibly satisfying
学到真芝士
about really getting something
还有解出高考最后一题
about solving puzzle or logic problem.
所带来的满足感是无与伦比的
Why don't you give it a try.
话都说到这份上了, 你又何不一试呢？